Jakub Tordoff

Full Stack Web Engineer

kubator21@protonmail.com https://jakubtordoff.com 414.210.7806

Overview

Experienced software developer well versed in many platforms and tools delivering quality software driven by business requirements. I am comfortable discussing requirements and then heads-down coding during the sprint to deliver them. A lively debater and a passionate collaborator, I understand that the team succeeds together. I enjoy tackling hard problems and designing solutions with the big picture in mind. I love experimenting with new frameworks, learning new patterns and automating the tedious tasks. I have a talent for leading technical projects and driving initiatives. My curiosity fuels my hunger for continually learning and improving my skill set.

Experience

American Family Insurance/ Senior Full Stack Software Engineer

October 2020 - PRESENT, Madison, WI

- Designed, collaborated and migrated several application to AWS successfully
- Effectively developed Angular components using NGRX, RXJS and best practices to deliver many business features
- Eagerly learned new technologies on the fly such as NestJS, React, AWS services, development patterns, performance optimizations and anything that is needed
- Organized, designed and developed highly efficient CICD processes that include security scans, testing, and deployment to many environments
- Maintained a monorepo that included SPAs and APIs along with all the dependencies and actively stayed on top of the latest frameworks and releases
- Supported production on call incidents for applications that were utilized by millions of users
- Reviewed, improved, and implemented complex reactive user interfaces

Northwestern Mutual / Test Engineering Manager

July 2020 - October 2020, Milwaukee, WI

- Managed a group of 10 people across 5 feature teams
- Improved development and testing processes to shorten the turnaround fimr for new features
- Successfully achieved company goals and propel testing maturity
- Got directly involved into projects to support testing practices and advocating for high quality coding and testing standards

Northwestern Mutual / Lead SDET

August 2016 - June 2020, Milwaukee, WI

- Leader of redesigning and utilizing modern test automation tools built upon Node, JavaScript and git
- Streamlined many testing efforts to deliver results quicker and allow for time to do exploratory testing
- Developed and maintained testing frameworks that supported applications with thousands of users
- Enforced best coding practice by reviewing merge requests with constructive

feedback

 Build many automation tools/frameworks from the ground up to meet specific needs

Education

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee / B.S. in Information Science and Technology

August 2016, Milwaukee

Undergraduate Coursework: Senior Capstone Website; Databases; Programming Languages; Networking, iOS and Android App development.

Projects

Personal Resume Website

https://jakubtordoff.com

Mock Amazon Website (2020)

https://gitlab.com/ktordoff13/amazon-clone

Messenger Real Time Chat

https://gitlab.com/ktordoff13/facebook-messenger-clone

Technologies

JavaScript, Bash, Git, CICD, HTML, CSS, React, Angular, yml, TypeScript, NestJS, AWS, Jira, Confluence, Node, GitLab, VS Code, wordpress, Postman, Jest, NX, Nrwl, Cypress, BrowserStack, SauceLabs, postgresql,